<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Giannis Kampiotis</title>
    <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages" />
    <updated>2024-09-17T23:26:06+03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to stop negative thoughts</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/how-to-stop-negative-thoughts.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/how-to-stop-negative-thoughts.html</id>

        <updated>2024-09-17T18:11:21+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Now that's a problem you wish you didn't have. Negative thoughts. Either about the future, or about a current situation. Worrying is the mind's default&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Now that's a problem you wish you didn't have. Negative thoughts. Either about the future, or about a current situation. Worrying is the mind's default state. It's not a bug (malfunction), it's a feature. That's how you survive. The problem is when the mind is left unchecked. Then it will get into a negative feedback loop and produce bigger and darker thoughts. That's pain.<br><br>I've found a solution.<br><br>The other day I was in my local Muay Thai class and our Instructor was teaching us about rhythm. Specifically, when we get attacked we should break the attacker's rhythm. The logic comes from a common practice: when attacking, you deliver more than one hits (that's a combo). So, when you get attacked, you block the attack. And since you expect more hits, you don't wait for them to land, you <strong>immediately</strong> counter-attack. That way you break the attacker's rhythm. The result: you get hit less.</p>
<figure ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/attacks-3.jpg" alt="getting attacked" width="546" height="290" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/attacks-3-xs.jpg 300w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/attacks-3-sm.jpg 480w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/attacks-3-md.jpg 768w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/attacks-3-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<figcaption >Getting attacked with a combo</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Do you see the analogy?<br><br>When the mind attacks with a negative thought, you don't wait for it to stop so you can feel better. You block it. Then, you attack it with a combo of positive thoughts. Whatever the situation you're in, there's something positive in there. I'm not talking about hopeful thoughts like "it will get better" and the likes. I'm talking about concrete positive thoughts. Like, how good you've handled similar situations in the past. Or, how you can find a lesson in that difficult problem which will lead to overcoming it. These kind of thoughts.<br><br>Yes, it's simple. Yes, it works. Also yes, it's difficult. So start practicing.</p>
<figure ><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/counterattacks.jpg" alt="counter attacks" width="546" height="299" sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/counterattacks-xs.jpg 300w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/counterattacks-sm.jpg 480w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/counterattacks-md.jpg 768w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/13/responsive/counterattacks-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<figcaption >Counter attacking stops the attacks so we can hit back</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>It will come to a point where you'll sense when the mind is going to attack you. Before it does, you'll quickly respond with positive thoughts.<br><br>Now, our Instructor prefers we don' get hit at all. Even if you block it, a hit is a hit. He wants us to get to the level that we can avoid incoming attacks. That's level 2, being proactive. But since it takes time to reach that body-fluency, and we're definitely gonna get hit, we need to go through level 1. Being reactive. That's blocking and then attacking back.<br><br>To continue our analogy: Level 2 is to avoid the attacks of the mind. To get to that state, you <strong>overwhelm it with positive thoughts.</strong> All the time. Be proactive and don't give to it the opportunity to generate negativity.<br><br>Practice.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>When are you ready to be a parent?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/when-are-you-ready-to-be-a-parent.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/when-are-you-ready-to-be-a-parent.html</id>

        <updated>2024-08-23T10:43:52+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    My partner expressed fear about the responsibility of having a child. When you raise a child, you're gonna make mistakes. You're gonna do things that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>My partner expressed fear about the responsibility of having a child. <br><br>When you raise a child, you're gonna make mistakes. You're gonna do things that you'll regret later. Or even, you're not gonna notice that they were mistakes. And you're gonna, in some way, mess up your child. Everything you do, every gesture, every word, every reaction, is imprinted into the child's brain. It is going to affect it. Good and bad, it's going to change your child.<br><br>Is this a reason to avoid having children? <br><br>It is not. From my point of view, there's only on prerequisite of having children. Have you mastered the basics? If you have, you're good to go. What I've learned from practising martial arts, cooking, sports, and making music is this: Master the basics and you're ahead of 99.9% of other people. That's it. No need for fancy, jaw-dropping, out-of-this-world performances. To win, to create beautiful art, to cook delicious food, all you need to be good at is the basics. <br><br>So what's the basics of parenthood? It's the basics of being yourself and a valuable member of society.<br><br>Do you know how to take care of yourself? How to learn? How to adapt? To give and take? How to love yourself and people around you? Do you know how to leave this place a little better than you found it? If you do, then you're going to be a good parent.<br><br>My love, you're going to be a wonderful mother.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Personalize the advice you get</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/personalize-the-advice-you-get.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/personalize-the-advice-you-get.html</id>

        <updated>2024-08-23T10:35:35+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    You can learn ANYTHING on the internet. If you know how to search, there's information for every subject. That's what I love about it. But&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>You can learn ANYTHING on the internet. If you know how to search, there's information for every subject.<br><br>That's what I love about it. But there's a problem. <br><br>There's so many ways of doing things where you can get conflicting instructions/advice for the same thing.<br><br>It's ok. I have a filter for that. <br><br>I carefully select what I read and listen to. If I feel it's just "content" for SEO or any other growth purpose, I ignore the information. If the information comes from people with authority, where they've already done the thing before, then I pay attention.<br><br>That's the difficult part about the internet. To find high integrity people. The easy part comes after you've gone through the first phase of curating "your people." Then you get recommendations from them. In that way. it's easier to expand than to begin.<br><br>There's another problem about this approach. Not actually a problem, but there's something to keep an eye on. <br><br>All this advice, instructions, playbooks, and how-I-did-it stories are personalized to the person sharing the information. They need to be adjusted to your personality.<br><br>If you blindly follow what they did, there's a high probability of failure. Or internal conflict.<br><br>I am guilty of this.<br><br>I've listened and read to all this people, with high qualifications and solid backgrounds, and when I tried to apply something I took from them, it usually didn't work.<br><br>"Of course it didn't work Giannis. It's how THEY did." <br><br>Now, don't get me wrong, the information they give, is solid. But it worked for their personality, for their network, for their time of doing it etc, etc. <br><br>It's best to take the information and ADJUST it to your personality.<br><br>The internet is a wonderful place. But we need to apply a very strict filter and then personalize the information we get.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to zig when everybody zags?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/how-to-zig-when-everybody-zags.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/how-to-zig-when-everybody-zags.html</id>

        <updated>2024-06-01T11:01:44+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Being a creative person right now sucks. You practice your craft for all these years and one day AI comes and does everything you can&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being a creative person right now sucks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You practice your craft for all these years and one day AI comes and does everything you can do, and so much more, with a click of a button.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why would anyone pay for your art? For your services? For anything you make? They can have it in an instant.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well… for you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I mean, if quality is not up to standard, yeah, you lost that job. But what is quality? Is it just high definition graphics? Is it a template of copywriting best practices? Or is it something else?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sure, what (Generative) AI can do right now, is novel. People are excited. In awe. But that fades away, it always does. What does not fade away is the impact of a creative piece. And to have impact, it needs a soul. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, a drawing can have a soul. A book can have a soul, a movie can have a soul as well. That’s quality. But in order to have a soul, it has to be created from something with a soul. Not a machine. It needs to come from a place of feeling. It needs imperfection. It needs some kind of resistance while it’s being made. That’s what makes it alive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So AI is exciting right now. But it will quickly fade away in the endless and endless of soulless “creative” products it will create.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You know what else excites people? Contrast.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And how can we use contrast in the era of digital, automated, super-fast, frictionless AI domination? How can we zig when everybody zags?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Go analog.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Analog is a slow, painful, manual, and a highly rewarding process. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, since everybody now is doing Generative AI creative works, when you go analog, you’re suddenly unique. People get amazed by your patience, and your love for your craft. You show them your process, your tools, you tell about your thoughts and feelings while you’re creating, and they form a connection with you. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while they wait for your creative work to be finished, to be polished, and get delivered to them, they get excited (again).</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The 5 Resets - Dr. Aditi Nerurkar M.D.</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/the-5-resets-dr-aditi-nerurkar-md.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/the-5-resets-dr-aditi-nerurkar-md.html</id>
            <category term="book-notes"/>

        <updated>2024-05-13T09:25:34+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This book is about stress and how to overcome it. It's very actionable, down to earth, and it is now in my "everyone should read&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div><figure class="align-left"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1699693116i/128082820.jpg" width="286" height="432" data-is-external-image="true"></figure></div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
<div>This book is about stress and how to overcome it. It's very actionable, down to earth, and it is now in my "everyone should read this" list.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>It is structured around 5 Resets and 15 Techniques. The following are my notes and interpretation of each reset and technique.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>What I use the most are the Rule of 2, the STOP-BREATH-BE, and Catalog Your Gratitude techniques.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The Rule of 2 states that the brain can handle up to two changes in routine at once. However most of the times, stress is related to more than two sources in our lives. Trying to fix everything at once is a mistake and it will end up in even more stress.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I have a personal story about that, years before I've read this book. I was a smoker, and I knew it was time to stop. I've attempted to stop before, but it didn't go well. But at that specific moment, I felt it was the time to do so. I had that feeling while I was smoking a cigarette. I even threw it half-finished. Then I decided that I needed to stop doing anything that triggers my smoking cravings. That was almost everything. I eliminated meat and alcohol from my diet, I started running and I even went completely vegan. What followed was ugly. I was a mess. I had even more anxiety. Panic attacks started to happen. Now I know why... Rule of 2!</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The STOP-BREATH-BE technique (read below) helps me transition between tasks or activities. It's like decompression. My mind feels lighter and actually, and I'm more present. I no longer feel that endless flow of everyday life. Now, every task,activity, or moment has a start and an end.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>As for the Catalog Your Gratitude technique (read below), even though I've had tried it before with not much results, I decided to give it another go. I thought that since I started following the book's advice, it would be something like a one-two punch. Well, it works. It works because when I'm having a good moment, whatever that might be, like an afternoon walk with my partner, a run with my dog, or admiring the beautiful colours of the sky, I now stop to notice it and say "that will go in my gratitude book tonight."</div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Resets</strong></div>
<ol>
<li>Get clear on what matters most</li>
<li>Find quiet in a noisy world</li>
<li>Sync your brain and your body</li>
<li>Come up for air</li>
<li>Bring your best self forward</li>
</ol>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Techniques</strong></div>
<ol>
<li>MOST Goal</li>
<li>Backwards Plan</li>
<li>Find Your Buried Treasure</li>
<li>Cure Your Popcorn Brain</li>
<li>Get The Sleep You Deserve</li>
<li>Stop-Breathe-Be</li>
<li>Breathe Easy</li>
<li>Take Twenty</li>
<li>Let Your Gut Lead The Way</li>
<li>Follow The "Goldlilocks Principle" For "Just Right" Stress</li>
<li>Learn The Magic of Monotasking</li>
<li>Fake Your Commute</li>
<li>Activate Your Sticky Feet</li>
<li>Catalog Your Gratitude</li>
<li>Express Yourself</li>
</ol>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
<h2>Reset 1: Get clear on what matters most</h2>
<div> </div>
<div>"[...] the First Reset is about identifying and making a plan toward less stress, while at the same time giving you something to look forward to every day."</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #1: Uncover Your MOST Goal</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>MOST Goal = <strong>M</strong>otivating, <strong>O</strong>bjective, <strong>S</strong>mall, and <strong>T</strong>imely</div>
<div> </div>
<div>A MOST Goal is about putting you in motion. To do that you need to know your "why." Once you've identified it, set a MOST goal. A MOST Goal is not about big changes, it's about small increments that pushes you and puts you in action mode.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>We each hold within our minds a mental picture or idea of the best version of ourselves. You’re reading this book because you’ve realized how much unhealthy stress has diverted you from that image. That best-self you envision may seem unattainable at this moment, but that’s your stress talking. The resilient you, which is still in there, knows the reason “why” you’re ready and willing to change. Your “why” helps tell you what matters most to you in your near future.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Once you identify your MOST goal, you will have the clarity and purpose to move forward.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I just keep the Objective word/definition for clarity. All other words are self-explanatory.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>O:</strong> Objective— Objective changes that you can regularly monitor for progress, no matter how tiny or incremental, will help propel you forward through the process of moving toward your MOST goal.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #2: Make a Backwards Plan</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>The point of this technique is to visualize how you will succeed getting to your goal. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>You set a roadmap by starting from the end-point and go step-by-step to figure out what's the previous step, until you reach the beginning. That is, now.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #3: Find Your Buried Treasure</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>Find what brought you joy when you were young and start doing it again. It doesn't matter what it is, riding the bicycle, playing the piano, painting, or anything else. Do it at least 10-20 minutes every day. Set a habit streak (calendar, app, or whatever).</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The point is to get into FLOW.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Every day, after doing the activity, congratulate yourself for doing it. You're rewiring your brain for happiness.</div>
<h2>Reset 2: Find Quiet in a noisy world</h2>
<div> </div>
<div>"Selma learned to protect her mental bandwidth using the techniques in the Second Reset. She found her quiet in a noisy world. She incorporated the elements of the media diet to overcome her primal urge to scroll, and reclaimed her brain and body’s need for rest and healing in the process. Since she no longer felt depleted, she was able to use her mental bandwidth to build meaningful connections through her soccer league. By focusing on disconnecting online, Selma found connection and a sense of belonging, and fun, offline."</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #4: Cure Your Popcorn Brain</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>Your smartphone is stealing your brain power. If you want it back you need to minimize your interactions. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Aim for half an hour or less every day. Disable all notifications and keep the phone away from sight. Even when disabled, if it's in view, the brain uses brain power for the POSSIBILITY of getting distracted.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>When detoxing you'll get withdrawal symptoms. Be prepared, find other ways to distract you when you feel the urge to pick up the phone.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #5: Get the Sleep You Deserve</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>You already know what to do here. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Sleep early, before 11. No screens a couple hour before sleep time. Try reading a book, listen to relaxing music, or do some breathwork. Keep the phone and the TV outside of the bedroom. </div>
<h2>Reset 3: Sync your brain and your body</h2>
<div> </div>
<div>"Lauren had found a way, through her Rule of 2, to slow down her runaway stress in spite of nothing else changing in her external environment. She still had the same challenges at home and at work, but she was able to better manage those life stresses. Lauren’s success was due to her progress, not to perfection.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Lauren needed something to help her self-soothe and cope with difficult emotions. [...] By addressing Lauren’s emotions gently and with compassion, through an exercise program, food log, and gradual dietary changes, she was able to reset her stress. Lauren had learned to sync her brain and her body."</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #6: Stop–Breathe–Be</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>One of my favorites from the book. Whenever you're about to start a task that kicks in your anxiety thoughts (usually repetitive tasks but not necessarily) STOP. Take a deep breath. Feel the air going in and out. Get back in touch with your body. Then go on with the new task.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>It reminds me of the taxing effect of context switching and the breathing technique Huberrman shared on his podcast. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Context switching, in escense, is about the brain power is required when the brain switches to a new task. That is why it has to readjust, find context and find the appropriate circuits to use. You might not feel it when it happens, but even when switching apps in your phone, your requesting to your brain to readjust. And this is a heavy load.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Huberman shared a breathing technique [find the podcast] in his podcast that research found is the most effective and quick for instant stress reduction. You take a deep breath and at the top of your lungs, take another short quick breath so you maximize the air in your lungs. Keep it for a few seconds and exhale slowwwwwly (longer than inhaling).</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #7: Breathe Easy</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>3 breathing techniques that instantly (and in the longterm) reduce stress levels:</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Diaphragmatic Breathing, 4-7-8 Breathing, Heart Centered Breathing.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Diaphragmatic Breathing</strong></div>
<div> </div>
<div>Very simply, make sure that when the breath goes in, the belly expands (deep breathing). This activates the parasympathetic system and is the first step to calm down. In the inverse, the first step to induce stress is shallow breathe. That is when the breathe goes in, it stays at chest (shallow breathing). You can do this anytime. I do this when exercising, between intense rounds, and whenever I'm feeling my stress levels rising.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>4-7-8 Breathing</strong></div>
<div> </div>
<div>At the core of this technique is that, if you exhale for more time than you inhale you lower your stress levels. So, inhale slowly for 4 seconds, hold the breath for 7 seconds, and exhale slowly for 8 seconds. Do it for 3-4 times. Take a break and do another set. </div>
<div>Easiest way to sleep.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong>Heart-Centered Breathing</strong></div>
<div> </div>
<div>For extreme moments of sadness or stress, use this technique to calm down. It's the same as the 4-7-8. Better to lay down, have on hand at your belly and the other at your heart. Inhale slowly for 4 seconds and exhale for 7 seconds. No need to hold. You'll feel your heart reacting to your breathing and it will ground you.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #8: Take Twenty</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>This technique is to set you in motion in an easy way. Whatever is going on with your life, taking a short walk helps to reduce stress, get in touch with yourself, and clear the mind.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>When you're out there walking, try not to distract yourself with music, podcasts, photos, etc. Notice how your body walks. How with each step your feet hit the ground. Notice how you breathe, how your hurt pumps, how the air feels.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #9: Let Your Gut Lead the Way</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>When you're stress, you crave for high-fat and high-sugar foods. Keep an eye on your diet, even when you're not in stress mode. Processed/unhealthy foods can be stress inducing.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>We now know about the microbiome and how it affects our body and mind. We even know about the special troops of the microbiome who are dedicated to alter our psychology based on what we ate a while ago. They're the psychobiome.</div>
<h2>Reset 4: Come up for air</h2>
<div> </div>
<div>"Your life is filled with demands and obligations. Every minute is accounted for, and you’re being pulled in many different directions. Your brain makes it all possible. But it needs rest and recovery to function optimally; it needs to come up for air. The four techniques in this reset—honoring your breaks with the Goldilocks Principle, learning to monotask, creating a fake commute, and activating your sticky feet to keep your mind present where your feet are—can all help support your brain to be the best it can be for you and for everyone else who depends on you."</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #10: Follow the Goldilocks Principle for “Just Right” Stress</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>Stress is <a href="https://plainenglish.com/expressions/feature-not-a-bug/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a feature, not a bug</a>.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>But too much stress, sudden or prolonged, is harmfull.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The simplest thing to do in the day is, when changing tasks, meetings, or whatever, take a few minutes to reset. Take a few breaths, feel your body, look outside the window, stretch a little. This gives the mind time to reduce the stress levels, and even more so, to consolidate the data you've been giving it. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>This is actually how we learn and the core truth of creativity. The more breaks (real brakes, not flicking through your phone) you take, the more time you give your brain to consolidate all the information it currently has. This way it can create new connections and make meaning of all this new information you've been giving it.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #11: Learn the Magic of Monotasking</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>Focus on doing one task at a time. Try to get into flow. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Find your limits, where your mind is focus and is not wandering. Is it 10 minutes? Try expanding to 15 minutes. is it 30 minutes? Go for 40-45 minutes. But don't overdo it. Take breaks. Do some breath work in between. Move the body.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #12: Fake Your Commute</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>If you work from home, you should incorporate time before and after work. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Before work, the mind needs some time to get prepared to switch to work mode. You could go for a walk and think/plan the day ahead. Go grab a coffee or something.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>After work, it needs time to decompress. Again, do something outside your house. </div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #13: Activate Your Sticky Feet</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>Stress and anxiety are very much related because they're induced by the same part of the brain. The amygdala. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>To combat anxiety, and the endless what-ifs it comes with, try this mindfulness technique.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Everytime you get the chance, try imagining your feet grounded to floor. Imagine them as sticky webs or tree roots. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>If you catch yourself spiralling into the what-ifs, say "be where my feet are."</div>
<h2>Reset 5: Bring your best self forward</h2>
<div> </div>
<div>"As you’ve learned in this Fifth Reset, words and imagery can be powerful tools to help you bring your best self forward during periods of maladaptive stress. That’s because humans are primarily visual learners, so most of us learn best when we have visual cues to rely on. As you embark on your journey to less stress, consider using that information to your benefit. Try incorporating visual cues and messages of self-love into your everyday life to help you move forward.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Display your MOST goal and the Backwards Plan to get there in plain sight on your fridge, so it’s easy to see every day. Create a daily reminder in your calendar for your walk or gratitude practice. Put up a weekly checklist with your Rule of 2 where you can see it; when you make it through each day, add a big checkmark and spend a few seconds basking in your sense of accomplishment. Use as many visual reminders as you need to remind yourself that you are stronger than your stress. And each morning, make a choice to choose yourself over your stress."</div>
<h2>TECHNIQUE #14: Catalog Your Gratitude</h2>
<div> </div>
<div>Keep a notebook close to your bed and before sleep, write 5 things you 're grateful for.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>It won't be always easy, and other times it you'll want to write a lot of things. Keep it simple. No need to write an essay, 5 bullet points and a few words are more than enough.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>It is proven that it works, but you need to give it time to work. Over time negative thoughts will disappear or at least be very weak and you'll be calm and centered.</div>
<h3>TECHNIQUE #15: Express Yourself</h3>
<div> </div>
<div>Writing helps processing of difficult situations, overcoming trauma, depression, uncover buried thoughts and worries, and many other benefits. For this technique, you need to go all-out. Hold nothing back. No one needs to know about what you wrote. You can destroy the paper after the exercise. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>Here are clear instructions on how to practice expressive writing in Pennebaker’s own words:</div>
<div> </div>
<div><em>I would like you to write about your very deepest thoughts and feeling about an extremely important emotional issue that has affected you and your life. In your writing, I’d like you to really let go and explore your very deepest emotions and thoughts. You might tie your topic to your relationships with others, including parents, lovers, friends, or relatives; to your past, your present, or your future; or to who you have been, who you would like to be, or who you are now. You may write about the same general issues or experiences on all days of writing or on different topics each day. All of your writing will be completely confidential. Don’t worry about spelling, sentence structure, or grammar. The only rule is that once you begin writing, continue to do so until your time is up.</em></div>
<h2>Some Book Highlights</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Stress is a whole-body phenomenon. We get waves of negative emotion, the familiar feelings of reaching a boiling point and experiencing doom and gloom. Whatever your sensory experience of stress might be, the origin of stress starts in the same place—the brain. Specifically, stress starts in an area called the hippocampus in the brain’s limbic system, according to scientists at Yale University. The limbic system is your emotional center, and the hippocampus is responsible for learning and memory. <br><br>So if stress is born in the same place as learning and memories are made, stress can be considered a learned response. And as with any learned response, it can be unlearned and retrained in a better way. That’s the first premise of why your brain can be rewired for less stress. <br><br>The second scientific principle behind rewiring your brain for less stress is based on one of the greatest discoveries in brain science: neuroplasticity. Before your eyes glaze over with this doctor-speak, it’s just a fancy word for your brain’s ability to change. It turns out that your brain is a muscle that grows and changes on the basis of the ever-changing conditions of your life. This applies to different parts of the brain, the connections between areas of the brain, and even among individual brain cells. If your biceps can get stronger by doing bicep curls, you can also train the muscle of the brain. It’s like pumping iron, but in this case pumping neurons. Your neurons, or nerve cells, make connections with each other to carry and transmit updated and new information between areas of the brain and throughout your body’s entire nervous system. They are good at finding the quickest route between two points, but it takes a number of trips to really establish a solid new connection. The brain is always establishing new routes and, the good news is, for the most part you can choose to strengthen the helpful ones through repetition. The more you engage in a new habit, the stronger that brain pathway becomes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>When it comes to how your brain responds to change, even positive change registers as stress to your brain. You may have the best of intentions to improve yourself, like Adam did, but you can make only two new changes at a time if you want those changes to last and be sustainable. Anything more than two at once and your system has a higher risk of overload. It wasn’t Adam’s fault that he couldn’t keep up with his plan. It wasn’t a lack of discipline or motivation. It was his biology.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Perhaps you’re thinking “I don’t know where to begin.” That’s not uncommon. Stress and burnout have jumbled your navigation tools and left you adrift. So the very first step is to shift your brain circuitry from survival mode into a healthier mental state of psychological safety and self-trust. Together, we’ll cover three techniques—Uncovering Your MOST Goal, Creating Your Backwards Plan, and Finding Your Buried Treasure—to help you crystallize your goals for less stress.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>You may have heard of the Comfort Zone. But there are three other zones that we move through when we’re faced with an acute stress or unexpected circumstances that push us out of our Comfort Zone: the Fear Zone, the Learning Zone, and the Growth Zone.<br><br>The three zones are a gradual, progressive journey we all take during setbacks. First, there’s the unexpected change that causes acute stress (Fear Zone). Our brains then move past survival mode and we gradually learn ways to adapt to this change (Learning Zone). Finally, we gain a new perspective from the experience (Growth Zone). One way or another, we learn something new from what we’ve been through. It doesn’t have to be an acute physical stress, such as Jeanette’s stroke. It can be a wide scope of unexpected changes: a job loss, having to move, the end of a relationship, the death of a loved one, a natural disaster, a dramatic change in finances, or discovering that a long-held belief isn’t true. What causes acute stress for one person can be very different from what causes it for someone else.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>To get out of this habit of negative self-talk, ask yourself the question that will help you silence your negative self-talk and get you into the Growth Zone: instead of asking “What’s the matter with me?” ask, “What matters most to me?”</p>
<p>We can only make changes that align with what matters most to us.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>I’ve found that for most of my patients there’s often a gap between knowing something and doing something. My job is to figure out how to close that gap. A lot of the work I do with patients is based on the foundational principles of motivational interviewing, which is a technique used in the medical setting to help patients overcome their barriers to change and close the gap. It’s a way to meet patients where they are to help them figure out what’s most important to them. Three of the most vital elements of motivational interviewing are having empathy, curiosity, and a lack of judgment when understanding how to close the gap between knowing and doing. You can’t do motivational interviewing on yourself, because it needs a trained practitioner for it to work. But you can lean into your own empathy, curiosity, and lack of judgment to help you figure out how to close the gap for yourself.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Future planning relies on your prefrontal cortex, which doesn’t function optimally when stressed. This is one reason why you’re prone to forget simple things like your keys, wallet, or phone during rushed and stressed mornings.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>What changed in Wes’s mindset to make change possible? He had discovered what mattered to him in the short term and created what I call his MOST goal.<br><br>Knowing what matters most to you is a powerful catalyst for change. Sometimes, it takes a little thought. If you’re having trouble coming up with what matters most to you, work on discovering your MOST goal.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness doesn’t help you get any closer to your “why” because happiness is a vague and moving target. We all want to be happy; it’s a universal yearning shared by every human being on the planet, but research has shown that we’re not very good at predicting what’s going to make us happy. For this reason, it’s important for you to get very specific about your endgame and MOST goal and those all-important steps of your Backwards Plan. They are concrete and tangible, whereas happiness isn’t.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Reorienting his life to pursue more intrinsically rewarding experiences rather than externally validating experiences helped Ryan reset his stress, which had a ripple effect on his sleep and anxiety. The sum of these changes was a balm to his nervous system.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hedonic experiences have a legitimate and valuable role as temporary circuit breakers for your stress. Distraction is a viable coping strategy for stress after a hard day’s work, and hedonic experiences are wonderful distractions when needed. You just can’t rely only on them for sustainable happiness over time.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>I read a quotation attributed to Carl Jung and asked her to reflect on it: “What did you do as a child that made the hours pass like minutes? Herein lies the secret to your earthly pursuits.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>The HPA axis—the connection between your hypothalamus, pituitary gland, and adrenal glands (see Chapter 2)—is a concrete example of the mind-body connection, because it quite literally connects parts of your brain with your body. One key tenet of the mind-body connection is that what’s good for your body is good for your brain and vice versa. When you do better, you feel better. And it’s all in the doing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>It may only be a short five seconds, but the Stop–Breathe–Be technique packs a long-lasting punch. It activates your mind-body connection because it trains your brain to notice your body and its physical sensations, along with your thoughts and emotions, in that precise moment, rather than mindlessly barreling forward like we all usually do. In that moment, it helps to regulate your stress response by asking you to take a brief inventory, and through your breath, it helps you regulate your nervous system away from stress. A complex biological phenomenon is at play during Stop–Breathe–Be. Did you know that your breath is the only physiological bodily process that is under both voluntary and involuntary control? You’re able to voluntarily control your breathing (like taking a deep breath), but when you don’t pay attention to your breathing, your body takes over for you involuntarily. How cool is that? No other bodily function can do that—not your heart beating, your gut digesting, or your brain thinking. This marvel of your human body is why your breath is the gateway to tapping into your mind-body connection.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>While scientists long ago had identified cortisol and the vagus nerve as key players in how your breath is linked to your emotions, they weren’t able to pinpoint exactly what was happening in the brain. Recently, a new study changed that. A group of scientists at Stanford University were able to pinpoint a small cluster of brain cells, which they called the pacemaker for breathing, that is responsible for linking your breath to your emotional state. It’s an important discovery that has been able to give us a much clearer cellular picture of what’s happening in your brain when you breathe deeply, and how your breathing can help you manage your unhealthy stress. Your brain’s pacemaker for breathing is the home of your mind-body connection, and your breath is a gateway to tap into it. The Stop–Breathe–Be technique is incredibly effective at activating your mind-body connection incrementally over time, but you also need a few more tools at your disposal when you’re faced with highly charged and intensely stressful moments.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Studies have confirmed Thompson’s findings. Chronic stress can prematurely shrink your brain through chronically high levels of cortisol. The good news is that brain shrinkage from too much stress is preventable and in some instances also reversible. Thompson offers us hope: “As soon as you know that’s true, you can look at ways of reducing your cortisol. That’s a very easy thing. We can get less stressed by exercising, walking, and taking breaks. There’s a lot of ways that you can take care of your brain.” While stress shrinks the size of your brain, exercise can help certain brain areas grow. Studies show that physical activity can thicken your prefrontal cortex and increase its connectivity and improve its function. That’s why, in part, exercise can help you have better problem-solving skills, attention, cognitive abilities, and memory.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Studies show that certain foods can directly impact your microbiome. In fact, the emerging field of nutritional psychiatry is focused primarily on how foods can affect your mental health, and its foundations lie in the gut-brain connection. Nutritional psychiatry can help guide you in choosing foods that can improve your stress.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Because Holly loved data, I shared a study conducted by Microsoft that compared brain scans of people who were in back-to-back meetings with brain scans of people who took short breaks. The study found that the brain scans in the group taking short breaks showed significantly less stress. Short, frequent ten minute breaks decreased the cumulative effects of work stress on the brain. This helped Holly become more enthusiastic about honoring her breaks.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Another reason why your inner critic is particularly loud during periods of unhealthy stress has to do with how stress impacts your sense of self-efficacy. As we explored in Chapter 3, when you achieve your MOST goal, your feelings of self-efficacy go up, which has a therapeutic effect on your well-being. The reason this is so important is because stress weakens your sense of self-efficacy. Unhealthy stress and its many uncomfortable sensations can make you feel out of control. When you’re feeling a lack of control, it’s easier to start talking to yourself in unkind ways. Your inner critic gets ahold of a megaphone. The voice gets louder, which adds to your feelings of inadequacy and your unhealthy stress. It’s a vicious cycle.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to deal with writer&#x27;s block</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/how-to-deal-with-with-writers-block.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/how-to-deal-with-with-writers-block.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-07T20:03:51+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Create anyway.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Create anyway.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bakis&#x27; Entrepreneurial Journey</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/bakis-entrepreneurial-journey.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/bakis-entrepreneurial-journey.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-06T13:35:23+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    He did not want this for the rest of his life. Bakis was a poor kid in a poor and dangerous area. He HAD to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>He did not want this for the rest of his life.</p>
<p>Bakis was a poor kid in a poor and dangerous area.</p>
<p>He HAD to get out of this situation. </p>
<p>He got a job at a factory that makes the cardboard core of paper rolls.</p>
<p>At the time, there was only one factory in the Country that made this product. The machine that made it was imported from another country and was very expensive. Because of this monopoly, the factory owner was arrogant, demanded unreasonable prices, and was not respectful of his customers.</p>
<p>Every day Bakis would load trucks with tons of this material. He got very strong. He was also operating the machine. </p>
<p>But was that it?</p>
<p>He had a job. He was not out in the streets doing crime, like many of his peers did. But he was not content. He wanted better for himself. He had to get out.</p>
<p>He had to start making more money. He knew he had to create his own business.</p>
<p>But what could he do? He was a labor man.</p>
<p>So, he decided to do what was already in front of him. He would make the same product from the same material. He would have his own factory.</p>
<p>The problem was that the machine was very expensive. And he was poor. </p>
<p>That didn't stop him.</p>
<p>He would copy and recreate it for cheap. So he started making drawings of the machine. He bought metals from scrapyards and then went to a blacksmith to build him his machine.</p>
<p>He found a little space to setup his new machine. He now needed customers.</p>
<p>He already knew which customers bought the product. All he had to do was knock on their door, tell them that there was a new factory in town. He would deliver the product cheaper and more reliably.</p>
<p>He now has a machine, a factory, clients and makes a lot of money.</p>
<p><strong>The lesson is this</strong>: Find what is already working. Something with validated demand. After you're in business, you can start thinking about unique value, selling propotitions, and all the fancy stuff.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Weekly Roundup 21-04-24</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/weekly-roundup-21-04-24.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/weekly-roundup-21-04-24.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-23T09:34:20+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    0.1% Ideas: 18 Useful Razors &amp; Rules - George Mack A collection of razors. The one I noted: The transfer of thoughts and ideas to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><a href="https://george-mack.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">0.1% Ideas: 18 Useful Razors &amp; Rules - George Mack</a></p>
<p>A collection of <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=razor+philosophy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">razors</a>. The one I noted:</p>
<p>The transfer of thoughts and ideas to different mediums unlocks different views of it.</p>
<pre><code>Creativity Razor - If struggling to think creatively about a subject, transform it: Turn a thought into a written idea. A written idea into a drawing. A drawing into an equation. An equation into a conversation. </code><br><br><code>In the process of transforming it, you begin to spot new creative connections.</code></pre>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://stratechery.com/aggregation-theory/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aggregation Theory - Ben Thompson</a></p>
<p>A theory for the new state of consumer-based businesses and how they are affected in the post-internet era.<br><br>Before, mass production and distribution was integrated so everyone bought and and read the same things. I got the same newspaper, and other products, as my neighbour. Distribution was localised.<br><br>Post-internet I can get my news, clothes, etc from wherever I want. The internet enabled "personalised" distribution. <a href="https://medium.com/@hagaetc/an-introduction-to-aggregation-theory-7cea63cc0e20" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The new scarcity is now that consumers only have 24 hours a day, and the hardest problem is now actually capturing the end-users’ limited attention. The big question now becomes: where do consumers actually look? The answer is, you guessed it: aggregators.</a></p>
<pre>First, the Internet has made distribution (of digital goods) free, neutralizing the advantage that pre-Internet distributors leveraged to integrate with suppliers. Secondly, the Internet has made transaction costs zero, making it viable for a distributor to integrate forward with end users/consumers at scale.<br><br>[...]<br><br>This has fundamentally changed the plane of competition: no longer do distributors compete based upon exclusive supplier relationships, with consumers/users an afterthought. Instead, suppliers can be commoditized leaving consumers/users as a first order priority. By extension, this means that the most important factor determining success is the user experience: the best distributors/aggregators/market-makers win by providing the best experience, which earns them the most consumers/users, which attracts the most suppliers, which enhances the user experience in a virtuous cycle.</pre>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://redef.com/original/age-of-abundance-how-the-content-explosion-will-invert-the-media-industry" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Age of Abundance: How the Content Explosion will Invert the Media Industry</a></p>
<p>The internet will move from programmatic recommendations to human curation.</p>
<p>This a 2016 prediction for the future state of media. And it has been a pretty spot on one. The shift from algorithms to curators is still in play and there's still time for anyone interested to create a personal brand through curation.</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-M6Q6rI7JII" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Don't choose your niche — be prolific instead </a></p>
<p>I guess that's a good advice not only about finding your niche but exploring life in general.</p>
<pre>I was thinking like an architect, trying to design my niche before getting started, when I should have been thinking like an archeologist, slowly uncovering my niche with every little thing I created.</pre>
<p>Keep creating whatever happens. Keep creating and you'll find your way.</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://www.julian.com/guide/startup/growth-channels" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Which paid and organic channels should you pursue?</a></p>
<p>Excellent guide on organic/paid growth channels.</p>
<p>Distribution-first is how I think. This guide makes it easier to think about growth costs (time or money) and if a business/idea is worth pursuing.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Hafs as A Service</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/the-hafs-as-a-service.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/the-hafs-as-a-service.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-22T17:56:42+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    (or how to test an e-commerce product idea) This is how I planned to create a flowers-and-sweets bundle gift service. It's a localised business that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p class="align-center">
    (or how to test an e-commerce product idea)
  </p>

  <p>
    This is how I planned to create a flowers-and-sweets bundle gift service. <br><br>It's a localised business that spans a few km around the area where I and my partner live.
  </p>

  <p>
    It's completely online, no store-front. People select a product and we deliver it to them.<br>That is because it's a test (an MVP) to see if there's demand for this product. If so, we could invest to a physical store in the area.
  </p>

  <p>
    The Hafs would be the name of the shop where we would sell flowers (purchase them), sweets &amp; coffee (make them). The reason I titled this The Hafs as a Service is because, for the test, we don't make any of the products. We just bundle them and distribute them.
  </p>

  <p>
    This is the moodboard we made:
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-5.55.45-PM.png" height="917" width="1901" alt=""  sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-5.55.45-PM-xs.png 300w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-5.55.45-PM-sm.png 480w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-5.55.45-PM-md.png 768w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/Screenshot-2024-04-22-at-5.55.45-PM-lg.png 1024w">
      
    </figure>

    <h1 id="the-frontend-what-happens-of-the-service-is-the-sequence-of-the-following-stepslessbrgreater">
      The frontend (what happens) of the service is the sequence of the following steps:<br>
    </h1>

  <p>
    1. Promote<br>2. Convert (website)<br>3. Compile (buy the items)<br>4. Deliver
  </p>

    <figure class="post__image post__image--center">
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/the-hafs-frontend.png" height="1800" width="2880" alt=""  sizes="(min-width: 920px) 703px, (min-width: 700px) calc(82vw - 35px), calc(100vw - 81px)" srcset="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/the-hafs-frontend-xs.png 300w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/the-hafs-frontend-sm.png 480w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/the-hafs-frontend-md.png 768w ,https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/media/posts/4/responsive/the-hafs-frontend-lg.png 1024w">
      
    </figure>

    <h1 id="this-is-the-backend-how-it-happens-behind-every-step">
      This is the backend (how it happens) behind every step:
    </h1>

    <h3 id="promote">
      Promote
    </h3>

  <p>
    To find new prospects, use ads. Facebook &amp; Instagram is where our clients mostly likely are. Since this is a test to find if there's demand in the area for our product, the ads should be shown only to people around that area.<br><br>When someone visits our site and buys the product, we collect their money and their email.<br>Then we go and buy the "ingredients" of our bundle and create the product.<br><br>Maybe even before someone buys, we could find ways to entice them to give us their email. This way, we build an email list and we can promote directly to them. Plus, we retarget them with our ads so it makes the ad system better and deliver better results.<br><br><b>New Prospects</b> &gt; Ads | Instagram &amp; Facebook<br><b>Previous Buyers</b> &gt; email them<br><br><b>These are the settings for the Meta ad platform:<br></b><br>For ad creatives no need to re-invent the wheel. Find what's working and replicate it with your own photos. I found [Creative OS]( [https://www.creativeos.io/](https://www.creativeos.io/), which is a collection of ad templates. Pick 4-5 templates, transfer them to Canva. Then take photos of your products and replace them in the templates.<br><br>I found Creative OS on twitter in a thread, from [Sam Thompson](https://twitter.com/ImSamThompson). It's about a simple way to set Meta ads. Pretty straight-forward. This is the [twitter thread](https://twitter.com/ImSamThompson/status/1772398912164209109).<br><br>I'll copy/paste the section about ads:<br>
  </p>

    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      Ad settings: <br>- No targeting<br>- Set-up your pixel in the Events Manager (Shopify makes it pretty easy). <br>- Set the budget at the ad set level. Start with 2-3x product price<br>- Set the ads to launch at 12:01am tonight &amp; publish. THEN DON'T TOUCH ANYTHING. Let them sit for 48-72 hours.<br>- If you get a purchase or two in the first couple days you have an interesting product on your hands... Once you see what's working you will optimize two main things: <br>- Landing Page/Product Detail Page = increase <br>- CVR Ad Creatives = reduce&nbsp;
    </blockquote>

  <p>
    Then I read something that got me thinking. This is from the article <a href="https://www.julian.com/guide/startup/growth-channels" target="_blank">Which paid and organic channels should you pursue?</a> from Julian Shapiro:
  </p>

    <blockquote id="lessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterpromotelessbrgreaterto-find-new-prospects-we-use-ads-facebook-andamp-instagram-is-where-our-clients-mostly-likely-are-since-this-is-a-test-to-find-if-theres-demand-in-the-area-for-our-product-the-ads-should-be-shown-only-to-people-around-that-arealessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterwhen-someone-visits-our-site-and-buys-the-product-we-collect-their-money-and-their-email-lessbrgreaterthen-we-go-and-buy-the-ingredients-of-our-bundle-and-create-the-productlessbrgreaterlessbrgreatermaybe-even-before-someone-buys-we-could-find-ways-to-entice-them-to-give-us-their-email-this-way-we-build-an-email-list-and-we-can-promote-directly-to-them-plus-we-retarget-them-with-our-ads-so-it-makes-the-ad-system-better-and-deliver-better-resultslessbrgreaterlessbrgreaternew-prospects-andgt-ads-or-instagram-andamp-facebooklessbrgreaterprevious-buyers-andgt-email-themlessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-these-are-the-settings-for-the-meta-ad-platform-lessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterfor-ad-creatives-no-need-to-re-invent-the-wheel-find-whats-working-and-replicate-it-with-your-own-photos-i-found-creative-os-httpswwwcreativeosiohttpswwwcreativeosio-which-is-a-collection-of-ad-templates-pick-4-5-templates-transfer-them-to-canva-then-take-photos-of-your-products-and-replace-them-in-the-templates-lessbrgreaterlessbrgreateri-found-creative-os-on-twitter-in-a-thread-from-sam-thompsonhttpstwittercomimsamthompson-its-about-a-simple-way-to-set-meta-ads-pretty-straight-forward-this-is-the-twitter-threadhttpstwittercomimsamthompsonstatus1772398912164209109lessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterill-copypaste-the-section-about-adslessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-lessbrgreaterad-settingsandnbsplessbrgreater-no-targetinglessbrgreater-set-up-your-pixel-in-the-events-manager-shopify-makes-it-pretty-easyandnbsplessbrgreater-set-the-budget-at-the-ad-set-level-start-with-2-3x-product-pricelessbrgreater-set-the-ads-to-launch-at-1201am-tonight-andamp-publish-then-dont-touch-anything-let-them-sit-for-48-72-hourslessbrgreater-if-you-get-a-purchase-or-two-in-the-first-couple-days-you-have-an-interesting-product-on-your-hands-once-you-see-whats-working-you-will-optimize-two-main-thingsandnbsplessbrgreater-landing-pageproduct-detail-page-increaseandnbsplessbrgreater-cvr-ad-creatives-reduceandnbsplessbrgreater-lessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterthis-is-from-the-article-which-paid-and-organic-channels-should-you-pursuehttpswwwjuliancomguidestartupgrowth-channels-from-julian-shapirolessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-lessbrgreatertwo-types-of-companies-have-the-best-chances-of-making-paid-ads-worklessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-high-margin-products-if-you-charge-customers-2000-for-a-mattress-or-10000year-for-enterprise-software-you-have-more-wiggle-room-to-experiment-with-ads-until-they-worklessbrgreater-products-with-a-high-word-of-mouth-or-referral-rate-if-new-users-refer-many-more-paying-users-then-you-may-be-able-to-tolerate-an-upfront-loss-on-acquiring-customers-via-adslessbrgreater-lessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-it-made-me-think-again-about-the-viability-of-this-test-that-is-because-now-we-have-to-think-about-the-sell-price-of-the-product-lets-say-we-go-for-50e-lessbrgreater-lessbrgreaterwe-have-4-expenses-1-flowers-2-sweets-3-packaging-4-adslessbrgreatersince-we-are-only-bundling-the-items-and-not-producing-anything-the-margins-are-going-to-be-thin-lessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterso-a-cost-estimation-of-one-bundle-lessbrgreater-1-flowers-15elessbrgreater-2-sweets-10-15elessbrgreater-3-packaging-1elessbrgreatertotal-26-30-eurolessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterthat-means-that-to-acquire-a-customer-through-ads-it-should-cost-us-less-than-30e-after-that-for-every-order-we-are-losing-moneylessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterso-now-the-hypothesis-is-that-we-could-sell-a-bundle-for-50e-and-still-be-profitable-or-at-least-not-lose-money-of-course-we-havent-calculated-the-costs-around-the-whole-business-shopify-subscription-other-online-tools-us-getting-paid-for-our-work-etc-lessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterbut-still-we-are-doing-this-to-see-if-theres-demand-if-there-is-we-should-find-ways-to-reduce-the-cost-to-create-one-bundle-and-make-the-margins-bigger-yamlessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-some-growth-questionslessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterhow-could-we-engineer-virality-word-of-mouthlessbrgreater-how-can-we-make-the-product-instagrammableandnbsplessbrgreater-how-do-we-encourage-people-to-make-stories-and-tag-uslessbrgreater-how-do-we-encourage-people-to-tell-their-friends-about-our-productlessbrgreaterlessbrgreater-some-retention-questionslessbrgreater-how-could-we-make-people-buy-againlessbrgreater-once-they-bought-which-channels-could-we-use-to-communicate-with-themlessbrgreater-could-new-promotions-or-new-product-drops-bring-back-previous-customerslessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterlessbrgreaterand-thats-about-itandnbsp" class="blockquote">
      Two types of companies have the best chances of making paid ads work:<br><br>- High margin products — If you charge customers $2,000 for a mattress or $10,000/year for enterprise software, you have more wiggle room to experiment with ads until they work.<br>- Products with a high word-of-mouth or referral rate — If new users refer many more paying users, then you may be able to tolerate an upfront loss on acquiring customers via ads.
    </blockquote>

  <p>
    It made me think again about the viability of this test. That is because now we have to think about the sell price of the product. Let's say we go for 50e.<br><br>We have 4 expenses. 1) flowers, 2) sweets, 3) packaging, 4) ads.<br>Since we are only bundling the items, and not producing anything, the margins are going to be thin.<br><br>So, a cost estimation of one bundle:<br>1) flowers: 15e<br>2) sweets: 10-15e<br>3) packaging: 1e<br>Total: 26-30 euro<br><br>That means that to acquire a customer through ads, it should cost us less than 30e. After that, for every order, we are losing money.<br><br>So now the hypothesis is that we could sell a bundle for 50e and still be profitable. Or at least not lose money. Of course we haven't calculated the costs around the whole business (shopify subscription, other online tools, us getting paid for our work, etc).<br><br>But still, we are doing this to see if there's demand. If there is, we should find ways to reduce the cost to create one bundle, and make the margins bigger (yam).
  </p>

    <h3 id="convert">
      Convert
    </h3>

  <p>
    OK, now we need to create the website. This is where we collect orders, money, and emails.
  </p>

  <p>
    Fortunately, this is easy thanks to Shopify. Signup for a Basic plan (24e/month) and then choose a template. I chose two free templates on the Food category.<br><br><a href="https://themes.shopify.com/themes/crave/styles/default/preview?surface_detail=themes-grid-second-row&amp;surface_inter_position=1&amp;surface_intra_position=10&amp;surface_type=all" target="_blank">Crave</a> and <a href="https://themes.shopify.com/themes/praise/styles/bold/preview" target="_blank">Ritual</a>.&nbsp;I also found another option, a more generic template but&nbsp; it includes a lot of extra plugins that can be very useful for upsells. It's <a href="https://solodrop.com/" target="_blank">Solodrop</a> and it's only $20/month. <br><br>It will take some time to setup everything but in general, very straightforward stuff.<br>
  </p>

    <h3 id="compile">
      Compile
    </h3>

  <p>
    This is the step where we choose 1) the flowers, 2) sweets, 3) and the packaging.<br><br>For flowers, do some online research or go to local stores and try and find cheap but beautiful flowers. I prefer dried flowers because they need no maintenance and have long shelf life.<br><br>For sweets, I think I prefer cookies because they're also low maintenance, but I'm open to surprises while researching.<br><br>For packaging, I quickly found some ideas on Temu. Like this and this.
  </p>

    <h3 id="deliver">
      Deliver
    </h3>

  <p>
    Well, not much to say here. Put everything together and drive to the order location. Ring the bell, smile, say something nice, and leave.<br>
  </p>

    <h1 id="some-growth-questionslessbrgreater">
      Some growth questions<br>
    </h1>

  <p>
    <b>How could we engineer virality / word of mouth?<br></b>How can we make the product instagrammable?&nbsp;<br>How do we encourage people to make stories and tag us?<br>How do we encourage people to tell their friends about our product?
  </p>

    <h1 id="some-retention-questions">
      Some retention questions
    </h1>

  <p>
    <b>How could we make people buy again?<br></b>Once they bought, which channels could we use to communicate with them?<br>Could new promotions or new product drops bring back previous customers?<br>
  </p>

    <h1 id="other-thoughts">
      Other thoughts
    </h1>

  <ul>
    <li>A subscription option for recurring deliveries.</li><li>	Add a super expensive offer. For example, if most bundles are around 50e, add a 200e option.</li><li>	Promote around specific holidays like Valentine's Day, Mother's Day, etc</li>
  </ul>

  <p>
    That's about it.
  </p>

  <p>
    The biggest question is 'how do I know if there's demand?' Well, if orders come easily and profitable (not expensive), there's repeated orders, and we find ourselves making a lot of bundles so we don't have the time to deliver, well...
  </p>

  <p>
    That's when you know.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Weekly Roundup 14-04-24</title>
        <author>
            <name>Giannis Kampiotis</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/weekly-roundup-14-04-24.html"/>
        <id>https://gkampiotis.github.io/gh-pages/weekly-roundup-14-04-24.html</id>
            <category term="weekly roundup"/>

        <updated>2024-04-16T12:20:20+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Podcast Notes Steph Smith: How to Make Your Writing Stand Out Episode metadata Episode title: Steph Smith: How to Make Your Writing Stand Out Show:&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1 id="podcast-notes">Podcast Notes</h1>
<h2 id="steph-smith-how-to-make-your-writing-stand-out">Steph Smith: How to Make Your Writing Stand Out</h2>
<h3 id="episode-metadata">Episode metadata</h3>
<ul>
<li>Episode title: Steph Smith: How to Make Your Writing Stand Out</li>
<li>Show: How I Write</li>
<li>Owner / Host: David Perell</li>
<li>Episode publish date: 2024-04-10</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="1952-incorporate-visuals-into-your-writing">[19:52] Incorporate visuals into your writing</h4>
<h5 id="✨-my-notes">✨ My Notes</h5>
<p>To make writing more understandable, use images. Even more efficient is to use moving infographiics. Made me thing of <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful/">/r/dataisbeautiful</a></p><h5 id="📚-transcript">📚 Transcript</h5>
<p>David Perell
To be able to story tell in this new way. Yeah, we’re really onto something interesting here. And if I’m a beginner writer and I’m thinking about how do I distinguish my work, maybe one answer is I’m going to get really good at using Canva or really good at using Photoshop or Figma. I don’t know what people use these days. And I’m going to get really good at having a distinct style and some unique way of telling stories through visuals. And then I’m going to share through the prism of those visuals. And that’s what people are going to know me for.</p><p>Steph Smith
Yeah. And there have been a few, a few people I’ve seen. I think there’s this guy James Eagle and this guy called like pie chart pirate, where if you go find them, I can, we can share the links, but they’ve just created these moving infographics, But they did it at a time where they had to create it themselves, they had to use, you know, Python or R to actually code the movement. However, there’s tools now like flourish where you can actually do this in seconds. And I, when I say it’s easy, I’m not just like, oh, it’s so easy and it’s not. You literally can within a few minutes go create these moving infographics as long as you’ve got a data set. And that’s by the way, also easier than ever.</p><hr>
<h4 id="4007-expose-yourself">[40:07] Expose yourself</h4>
<p> ✨ My notes
Exposing yourself, your interests, your desires, you fears, your resolutions, and every other thing that makes you human, is how people connect with you. In the end, this is authentic personal branding.</p><h5 id="📚-transcript-1">📚 Transcript</h5>
<p>David Perell
The other thing that I’ve come to appreciate is to go back to Kevin Kelly, he has a line where he says, just tell your story with uncommon honesty. And I think that I’d spent so much of my early writing time trying to be smart or trying to look impressive or seem knowledgeable, oh, I need to learn all these things. Like, I’m not enough. I have to learn, learn, learn, learn, learn, and then the residue that learning will turn into my writing, all that sort of stuff. But a lot of the things that people resonate the most with is, here’s what I struggle with, here’s the stupid mistakes I made. I was an idiot in this way and that way. And I grew through this. And let me just tell that story. </p><p>And it’s actually fairly easy for me to express that. And I don’t even feel like it’s very insightful. And yet people seem to really resonate with that. And that is truly astounding to me. It is.</p><p>Steph Smith 
But I also think that’s why people, including myself, had things go viral in their very earliest of days, right? Because that’s when they don’t care who’s reading, listening, because no one in theory is. And so I think that that true, like, honesty, rawness, where you’re just like, I have something to say. And it could be about your life or something happening in the world. And like you’re saying, there’s no intention to rile people up because there’s this expectation that no one is listening. This is more an exercise for yourself. When you do that, I think that’s why those early pieces are really important.</p><h4 id="010127-crafting-messages-with-musicality">[01:01:27] Crafting Messages with Musicality</h4>
<h5 id="✨-my-notes-1">✨ My Notes</h5>
<p>Made me think of the days I was making repetitive music. Writing in a manner that is repetitive and hypnotic, but not boring, is something I could explore in my writing.</p><h5 id="📚-transcript-2">📚 Transcript</h5>
<p>David Perell
Well, I think all these things are interconnected. And one of the major lessons from music is that there’s a lot of craft in the way that you encode a message. And music, having things, the way that things are structured, the way that things are written, almost having a lyricism about it. And the flow, the pacing. So you listen to lose yourself by Eminem. This is the lamest thing that I’m about to do, but whatever. His father’s sweating knees, weak arms are heavy. There’s vomit on his sweater already. You just remember these things. And to go back to what we were saying, I think music and poetry, there are a lot of lessons in terms of how you encode ideas. Don’t ask what your country can do for you, but what you can do for your country. Speech writing, hamlet to be or not to be. That is the question whether it is nobler to suffer slings and arrows about rages, fortune or bi opposing, and them to die to sleep to sleep or chance to dream. These things are when you memorize them, you get a sense for rhythm. And it is so easy when you’re writing to only focus on substance and forget about style. But poetry and music and speech writing is more about the style than the substance. And what does it say that I first read these pieces of poetry or listen to these songs? Sometimes 20 years ago, 15 years ago, and I still remember them. It makes me reconsider what my priorities are as a writer.</p><p>Steph Smith
It makes me, as we’re talking about this, think through because I am a creator that cares about a long term horizon. I’m a terrible singer, so that’s not a path for me. But to your point, incorporating musicality, and that doesn’t mean turning it into a beat, but how do I create something? These taglines that stick, these ideas that stick, even that line is that sticky. How do I create something that actually isn’t just a moment in time that happens to trend on Hacker News? That not just I’m proud of, but has this rhythm, has this thing that people into it and internalize for longer than the few minutes of they spend with you?</p><hr>
<h2 id="how-i-reverse-engineered-a-100-million-exit---jason-lemkin">How I Reverse Engineered A $100 Million Exit - Jason Lemkin</h2>
<h3 id="episode-metadata-1">Episode metadata</h3>
<ul>
<li>Episode title: How I Reverse Engineered A $100 Million Exit - Jason Lemkin</li>
<li>Show: My First Million</li>
<li>Owner / Host: Hubspot Media</li>
<li>Episode publish date: 2024-04-10</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="2252-anchor-around-the-comps-and-remove-friction">[22:52] Anchor Around the Comps and Remove Friction</h4>
<h4 id="✨-my-notes-2">✨ My Notes</h4>
<p>Simple SaaS pricing. Check the competition and price your solution the same way. If you deviate too much you confuse the customer (because they know what’s in the market) and it adds friction. And the main thing, in business, is to remove friction.
Remove friction.</p><h5 id="📚-transcript-3">📚 Transcript</h5>
<p>Jason Lemkin
I think that pricing is over-discussed. And I’ll tell you why. There are, we have all now bought 200, at least most businesses have bought over 200 SaaS apps. Okay. It’s 200 pieces of business software. </p><p>And we all kind of know what stuff should cost. Like we know what Notion should cost. We know what hub spot should cost. We’re on Riverside. I don’t know what Riverside is. What do you guys pay? 300 bucks a month. Okay. Like, okay, let’s say you pay 300 bucks, 400 bucks a month. Now if someone else has a better version of Riverside and they want 50,000, you’re going to like a month, you’re going to kind of b*t, right? </p><p>But what if someone had something that was better than Riverside? It was $30 a month. It would seem too cheap. Right? It would seem too cheap. </p><p>My point is there are organic price points. And what you want to do is anchor around them, go figure out the couple of products out there that are most similar to yours and charge the exact same way and either charge the same pricing or if you’re nervous, charge a smidge lower, 10% lower, 20% lower. </p><p>If you charge too much lower, you’re telling the market you’re not as valuable as Riverside, right? Or you’re not as valuable as hub spot. And you can actually, customers will bounce off you if you’re too cheap. If you’re too cheap, they will get confused. </p><p>So anchor around the comps. </p><p>If you’re truly 10 times more valuable than Riverside, okay, and Riverside’s very good. We’re using it to record the session. If you’re 10 times more valuable, maybe charge twice as much because you’re telling the market we’re 10 times more valuable than the leader, right? We’re 10 times more valuable. </p><p>But whatever you do, founders that say there’s no one like us, there’s no comp, try harder. It doesn’t have to be the same as you. Just it feels the same. It feels a similar amount of value, a similar type of utilization. Do I use it eight hours a day? Do I use it once a month? Do I use it as an API? Is it metered? Is it per seat? Just there’s hundreds of apps like you. </p><p>And if you price similar to similar value apps, you remove friction. You remove friction from the sales process. And that’s what you want to do until you’re really big. </p><p>This is why we also under-price founders because you want to remove friction. We want every deal to close in the early days, don’t we? We want every deal to close. And so your job as a founder, if you want to scale, if you want to reverse engineer things, your job, because no one else in your company will do this, your job is every day to relentlessly Remove friction from your customer acquisition process, remove friction. </p><p>And people added it scale. The classic one is contact me. You go to a website. You’re all excited to buy on your own. And I got to talk to a rep. Well, there’s a couple reasons. One reason is they’ve gotten to hundreds of millions of revenue. And they actually want to add friction to the sales process. But you don’t want to do that until you’re at tens of millions of revenue. You want to every day come into work. And if you can’t do anything else on your company, remove friction. How can I make sign-up easier? How can I add single sign-on? How can I make an easier to check out from my e-commerce thing? How can I make the bundle easier? How can I make support better? </p><p>Remove friction. Remove friction. </p><p>The support that happens automatically in seconds rather than waiting five minutes on the dumb bubble, that removes friction, doesn’t it? Whatever it takes, remove friction.</p><hr>
<h2 id="dr-adam-grant-how-to-unlock-your-potential-motivation--unique-abilities">Dr. Adam Grant: How to Unlock Your Potential, Motivation &amp; Unique Abilities</h2>
<h3 id="episode-metadata-2">Episode metadata</h3>
<ul>
<li>Episode title: Dr. Adam Grant: How to Unlock Your Potential, Motivation &amp; Unique Abilities</li>
<li>Show: Huberman Lab</li>
<li>Owner / Host: Scicomm Media</li>
<li>Episode publish date: 2023-11-27</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="2633-topic-how-to-make-a-boring-assignment-interesting--better-grades">[26:33] Topic: How to Make a Boring Assignment Interesting &amp; Better Grades</h4>
<h3 id="✨-my-notes-3">✨ My Notes</h3>
<p>How to get interested in everything: Find curiosity gaps </p><h5 id="📚-transcript-4">📚 Transcript</h5>
<p>Dr. Adam Grant
Now, I think obviously in the experiment, lying was an easy way to show the effect. But in real life, I think the way that you want to apply this is to say, all right, I’ve got to find something about this task that’s interesting to me. And then in the process of explaining it to somebody else, I’m going to convince myself because I’m hearing the argument from somebody I already like and trust. I’ve also chosen the reasons that I find compelling as opposed to hearing somebody else’s reasons. And so I think this goes to the point that you were making, which is if you’re trying to find a hook to make a topic intriguing, you’ve got to figure out, okay, what is it that would make this Fascinating to me? And in a lot of cases, what you’re looking for is a curiosity gap. I think social scientists like to talk about curiosity as an itch that you have to scratch. So there’s something you want to know and you don’t know it yet. So I would say I tell my students often, like, take your least favorite class and find a mystery or a puzzle. Like something that you just do not know the answer to. Like, actually, I’ve talked with our kids about this. Like, what really happened to King Tut? Do you know? Can you get to the bottom of that? And all of a sudden, you’re like, I wonder, I need to Google it. And then I need to see if Wikipedia has credible information on this. And the more you learn about that, the more intriguing it becomes. And I think that’s the beginning of the process of finding intrinsic motivation.</p><p>Andrew Huberman
I see. So inherent in your answer is the idea that there’s something wired into our neural circuits and therefore psychology that curiosity as a verb, the act of being curious and seeking Information where, well, and I should say, I define curiosity and I hopefully you’ll disagree with me or agree either way. It doesn’t matter as long as we can get a bit deeper understanding. I define curiosity as a desire to find something out where you are not attached to a particular outcome.</p><hr>
<h2 id="shaan-puri-3-principles-to-master-storytelling--how-i-write-podcast">Shaan Puri: 3 Principles to Master Storytelling | How I Write Podcast</h2>
<h3 id="episode-metadata-3">Episode metadata</h3>
<ul>
<li>Episode title: Shaan Puri: 3 Principles to Master Storytelling | How I Write Podcast</li>
<li>Show: How I Write</li>
<li>Owner / Host: David Perell</li>
<li>Episode publish date: 2024-03-20</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="4559--viralretweetable-writing-start-w-the-emotion-lol-wtf-wow-etc">[45:59] *** Viral/Retweetable Writing: Start w/ the Emotion (LOL, WTF, WOW, etc)</h4>
<h4 id="✨-my-notes-4">✨ My Notes</h4>
<p>What emotion do I want my piece of content to give? Start with that. Then make sure that it truly delivers that emotion. Impact.</p><h5 id="📚-transcript-5">📚 Transcript</h5>
<p>This guy Chris Quigley, he ran an advertising agency that would make videos go viral. </p><p>And at the time I was like, going viral is like a lottery ticket. Like, how do you do a viral video? I don’t know. It’s just like something amazing must happen. </p><p>So I go, what’s your hit rate on virality? Like one out of 100, two out of 100. He goes, no, like eight out of 10. I go eight out of 10. And he’s like, yeah, look, he showed me their their views. I was like, how do you do this? </p><p>He’s like, well, you know, over time, the more viral videos you make, you have like a base of an audience. But he’s like, that just gets you like some people will see it. But how viral goes is how much they share it. </p><p>He goes, so what we do is we work backwards from an emotion. He goes, the only things people will share is things that are L O L   W T F   O M G . Like all the acronyms for all the emotions. So like, oh my God, wow, like, ha, ha, right? </p><p>Like if it doesn’t do that, nobody will share it. So he goes, we first start with this is the desired reaction we have. Then we’ll write a script or write a blog post or whatever. And then we’ll go check. Do we think that’s going to create this reaction? Somebody? No? All right. Plus, juice it up. How do we make it more funny? How do we make it more? Outraging. How do we make it more? Endearing and heartwarming, like whatever those are. </p><p>And so once I heard that three times, I was like, okay, I get it. I need to create a reaction of reaction out of the average person just in the bedroom or at the desk. And I need to start with the emotion, my target emotion, and then work backwards from that. Write the thing that will create that emotion.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
